Previously on Transformers: Prime...
在上一集里
A crash landing, buried here for centuries.
飞船迫降 看来已经坠毁几百年了
These Autobots didn't perish in the crash.
这些汽车人并不是死于飞船失事
They are displaying the effects of a virus.
他们的症状…像是感染了病毒
If a cure exists, Megatron maybe the only one who knows it.
如果真的有解药 威震天可能是唯一知道底细的人
You must enter his brain and find it.
你们必须进入他的大脑 找到解药！
What are you doing inside my head?
你在我的脑子里干什么？
We have the formula, disconnect Bumblebee, now!
配方已经到手 断开大黄蜂的驳接 快！
No, take me!
不！带我一起走！
I'm out! Hahahahahaha...
我出来了
Follow the light. Good, good.
眼睛看着光 好 好
I wouldn't advice anything strenuous, Optimus,
我建议你不要做剧烈运动 擎天柱
but it appears that your systems have fully recovered from the Cybonic plague.
尽管目前看来 你的系统已经从灰死病的侵蚀中完全恢复了
Thanks to your medical expertise, old friend.
幸好有你高明的医术 老朋友
It was your scout who braved unknown territory to locate the cure.
幸好有你的侦察兵 单枪匹马 深入虎穴找到解药
Lucky for us Megatron was still alive.
幸好威震天还活着
Yea, I actually said that.
没错 的确很走运
What matters is that you are on the mend, Optimus,
重要的是 你的病情有所好转 擎天柱
while Megatron...
威震天现在…
Bee's right, 'did my best to finish Megatron's story.
小蜂说得对 我很想手刃威震天
Just couldn't stick around long enough to see how it ended.
可当时来不及看他咽下最后一口气
It is a matter of time before Optimus discovers all is not right with you, scout.
擎天柱早晚会发现你心怀鬼胎 侦察兵
I must reclaim my body,
我必须取回我的身体
which means taking complete and total control of yours.
也就是说 眼下我要完完全全地控制你的身体！
Basketball by way of Cybertron.
塞博特恩式篮球比赛
Let the games begin!
比赛正式开始！
Yeah, go Bulk!
漂亮！小隔加油！
Come on, best two out of three.
来吧 我们三局两胜！
Bee, you are in the clear!
小蜂 现在后防空虚！
Dunk it, Bee!
扣篮啊 小蜂！
Bumblebee, quit hugging the ball!
大黄蜂 小心持球违例！
Ngrr, flagrant foul!
恶意犯规！
Dodge Ball by way of Cybertron.
更像是塞博特恩躲避球比赛
Bee, hoop's over there.
小蜂 篮筐在那边
Bee, you OK?
小蜂 你没事吧？
Yea, three out of five.
好吧 那就五局三胜
If I am to return my body,
如果我想回到自己的身体里去
I must first restore its functionality.
必须先恢复身体的各项功能
How did I escape annihilation?
我当初是如何逃过一劫的？
Of course, Dark Energon!
对了 是黑暗能量！
Starscream!
红蜘蛛！
Knock, knock. Is anyone in there?
当当当 有人在里面吗？
No. Oh well...
没有？那好吧…
Seems I possess the only thing
看来我拥有唯一一个
that would allow you to rise off that slab and walk again.
能让你从病榻上重新站起来的东西
My dearest Megatron...
最最亲爱的威震天…
The only scrap left on this planet,
这星球上仅存的碎片
plucked from your very spark chamber.
正是从你的火种室里拔出来的
But it cannot restore your mind.
但它并不能恢复你的意识
The Decepticons need a leader,
霸天虎需要的是首领
not a decorative centerpiece.
不是高高在上的废铁
And I will convince them that I am the true heir to your throne,
我会向他们证明 只有我才配继承你的王位
with a plan so epic...
我要勾画一副宏伟蓝图…
Not even the mighty Megatron could've conceived it?
连强大的威震天 也构思不出的那种蓝图？
Eh, that was the idea, Knock Out.
呃 我就是这么想的 击倒
How long have you been there?
你过来多久了？
Long enough.
很久了
And it's Commander Knock Out to you,
请叫我击倒指挥官
once and future Lord Starscream.
永恒的王者 红蜘蛛陛下
Raf? Class is starting.
拉夫？已经上课了
Bumblebee never picked me up for school,
大黄蜂没来送我上学
and his comlink is off again.
他的通讯链也关了
Any idea where he is?
你知道他在哪里么？
Yes, go on scout, obey my will!
对 继续 侦察兵 服从我的意志！
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
I needed that!
那东西我还有用呐！
What has got into you?
你脑子里究竟在想什么？
You are seeing Megatron's face?
你看见威震天了？
Bumblebee's complaining of intermittent visions.
大黄蜂说 他总能看见断断续续的影像
Waking nightmares, if you will.
可以说是种梦魇
But, you said Bee was fine when you checked him over.
但你给小蜂做全面检查时 说他很健康
Physically,
身体很健康
but the experience he endured seems to be having a temporary effect on his psychy.
但一些不堪回首的经历 似乎对他的心理造成了暂时影响
This induced power down should force Bumblebee's mind to rest and recover.
这次诱导性休眠 可以强行停止并恢复大黄蜂的意识
Prime, you spot any Decepticons wearing hula skirt lately?
擎天柱 你最近发现穿草裙的霸天虎了吗？
No, Special Agent Fowler. Why?
没发现 福勒探员 又怎么了？
Coz I was hoping you have a lead on the Cons
我以为你有虎子的线索呢
that busted into the Kauai Naval Observatory.
他们破坏了夏威夷考艾岛的海军气象台
Place look like it was hit by an army of wrecking balls.
那里看起来像是被军队强拆了一样
Why would Cons break into an Observatory?
霸天虎干嘛要进攻一个气象台？
Does the Heuck Nigoghossian ring any bells?
“霍伊克・尼哥高西安”这个名字耳熟么？
The space telescope!
是那个太空望远镜！
As of last night missing its primary lens.
昨晚 它的主镜头被盗了
It's difficult to guess Starscream's intent
很难猜测红蜘蛛有什么意图
without knowing where the lens has been taken.
我们并不知道镜头的下落
Good thing's the lens has a tracking device.
好在那个镜头有跟踪装置
The Arctic? Great!
北极？太好了！
Another chance to freeze our sparkplugs off.
又可以体验火种被冻僵的感觉了
Hew... That's a ND-7 class, biggest unminable energon deposit there is.
是ND-7级别的区域 那儿的能量矿面积最大 但无法开采
Unminable until Starscream melt his way down to it.
除非红蜘蛛能想办法让冰面融化
With the help of the lens.
那个镜头可以派上用场
Melting a glacier that size would cause sea levels to rise and demolish coastal cities.
融化那片大冰川 会使海平面上升 淹没沿海城市
Let the rain of Lord Starscream... begin.
让红蜘蛛陛下赐予的甘露…降临吧
So I blow pass the finish line.
我风驰电掣般冲过终点线
Then my other sister Plaura asked how I got so good at racing games.
然后另一个姐姐问我 为何这么擅长赛车
And I told her I know a guy who knows cars.
我就说 我认识一个非常懂车的家伙
Raphael, I'm afraid Bumblebee can't hear you in power-down mode.
拉斐尔 恐怕大黄蜂听不见你说话 他正处于休眠模式
It's getting late. Why don't I bridge you home to your family?
太晚了 要不然 我先送你回家吧？
Because I told Bee I'd stay. He's family, too.
我跟小蜂说过 我要留下 他也是我的家人
Don't be ridiculous. You are not even the same species.
别扯了 你们根本不是同一个物种
That's being related.
那叫“亲戚”
It's not the same thing. I'll show you.
“亲戚”跟“家人”是两回事 我拿给你看
This is my family.
这是我的全家福照片
Hm, hm. Yes, very nice.
嗯 嗯 是的 很好
Very large.
是个大家庭
Sometimes I can shout and no one hears me.
有时即使我大喊大叫 也没人理我
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
是是是…
But Bumblebee always listens.
但是大黄蜂总会听我说话
And I can understand him.
我也能理解他的滴滴声
I'm not sure why, but I do.
不知为什么 我全能听懂
A lot different than our last polar visit.
和上次的极地旅行相比 变化很大
Feels like summer.
感觉像是夏天
Here, that's a bad thing.
看 问题出在那儿
Autobots, remember the end run on Polyhex?
汽车人 还记得在乱魔城的那次迂回进攻吗？
Raphael, I'm going to the supply vol to see if I can find parts to repair this.
拉斐尔 我要去仓库找些零件来修理这个
You know what that means?
你应该明白我的意思吧？
"Don't touch anything."
“什么都别碰”
Wait til I see this new laptop I'm saving up for, Bee.
先看看这台新手提电脑 我存钱要买的 小蜂
Bee?
小蜂？
Bumblebee, wait!
大黄蜂 等等！
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
What did you do?
你碰什么了？
Nothing, Bumblebee just got up and...
什么也没碰 大黄蜂是自己站起来的…
He was in power-down.
他明明处于休眠模式！
Where does he think he's off to?
他这是要去哪儿？
Where is it? Where?
它在哪儿？在哪儿？
These are the coordinates for the site of our previous battle with Megatron's undead.
这些坐标指向我们上次 遭遇威震天不死大军的地方
Maybe we should call Optimus?
我们是不是该通知擎天柱？
Optimus is busy preventing a polar ice cap from melting.
擎天柱正忙着解决极地冰盖融化的事
We need to handle this on our own.
我们得自己处理了
Bumblebee? What have you been doing?
大黄蜂？你干什么去了？
Dark Energon?
黑暗能量？
Bee, what are you doing?
小蜂 你在干什么！
Bumblebee, please! I know you are in there!
大黄蜂 拜托！我知道你的意识还在！
You have to fight whatever is making you do this!
你必须和控制你意识的东西做斗争！
Ratchet, are you OK?
救护车 你没事吧？
I'm fine. More importantly, is bumblebee?
我没事 问题在于 大黄蜂怎么了？
I fear the time spent in Megatron's mindscape
我担心他在威震天的意识里逗留太久
is causing him to think like a Decepticon.
导致他的思维越来越像霸天虎
Bee's not a Con!
小蜂才不是虎子呢！
Agreed, but we need to find out exactly
我同意 但我们必须弄清楚
what Bumblebee intends to do with that shard.
大黄蜂拿着那个碎片要做什么
The only one who knew of the Dark Energon
唯一一个了解黑暗能量的人
was Megatron.
就是威震天
Bumblebee has Megatron's memories?
大黄蜂拥有威震天的记忆？
Worse, Megatron is occupying Bumblebee's mind.
可能更糟 威震天在控制大黄蜂的思想
What?
什么？
How could I've been such a fool!
我怎么那么蠢！
The cortical psychic patch acted as a two-way condulet.
大脑皮层通灵驳接是个交互式的过程
When Bumblebee returned to his own mind,
当大黄蜂的意识回归身体时
Megatron followed.
威震天也紧跟其后
And now Bumblebee--
而现在大黄蜂――
Megatron has bridged to nearly the same coordinates Optimus used.
应该说威震天 已经把自己传送到擎天柱的位置附近
Stay here.
你留在这里
No. Bumblebee needs me!
不 大黄蜂需要我！
Of course he does.
他的确需要你
Yes! I love when a plan comes together!
是的！计划终于按部就班地实施了！
Autobots!
汽车人！
Please, Lord Starscream. Allow your second-in-command the honor.
劳驾 红蜘蛛陛下 请给你的副官一次立功的机会
Breakdown, total them!
打击 消灭他们！
The Decepticon warship!
霸天虎的战舰！
Did Bumblebee do this?
这是大黄蜂干的吗？
I fear Megatron's mind is dominant.
恐怕威震天的意识占了上风
And clearly he came here for one purpose--
而且很明显 他来这里只有一个目的――
to use the Dark Energon to resurrect his own body.
用黑暗能量来修复自己的身体
No. Bumblebee won't let him.
不 大黄蜂不会让他得逞的！
Like he didn't let Megatron hurt me back at base.
刚才在基地 他就没让威震天伤害我
I hope you're right.
希望你是对的
Ratchet, don't hurt Bumblebee!
救护车 别伤害大黄蜂！
That's not Bumblebee!
那不是大黄蜂！
Bumblebee, no!
大黄蜂 住手！
Remember who you are, remember me!
想想你是谁 想想我！
I know you'll always listen to me, no matter what!
我知道无论如何 你都会听我说话的！
That's right, Bee. It's me!
没错 小蜂 是我啊！
Unbelievable!
怎么会这样！
Farewell, Megatron!
永别了 威震天！
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee can't hear you anymore!
大黄蜂再也听不到你说话了！
As mush as I want you to leave Bumblebee's body,
虽然我很想让你离开大黄蜂的身体
I can't let you go back to your own!
可我决不让你回到自己的躯壳！
Decepticons, your rightful lord and master has returned!
霸天虎们 你们至高无上的主人已经回来了！
Finish these pests!
把这些虫子消灭掉！
I have my own extermination to perform.
有个死刑 我要去亲手执行
How about I put you on ice?
把你冻成冰块怎么样？
Don't the Bots seem... understaff?
汽车人是不是…缺乏人手？
Uhhh... What good is a second-in-command who fails to watch the rear!
一个顾前不顾后的副官 我要他何用！
Get out of my way!
给我滚开！
No!!
不！！
Optimus!
擎天柱！
Megatron's greatest mistake
威震天犯下的最大的错误
was ever allowing you to live, Prime!
就是放你一条生路 擎天柱！
Megatron...
威震天…
He's back.
他回来了
Lord... Megatron, you... are... you are healed!
威震天…陛下 您…这…您痊愈了！
Praise the Allspark, it is a miracle!
感谢火种源 奇迹发生了！
Oh, it will be a miracle, alright, Starscream.
喔 奇迹会发生的 红蜘蛛
if you survive what I have planned for you!
这要看你能不能逃过我的惩罚！
But the Autobots! Optimus! Right there, waiting for you!
可那些汽车人…还有擎天柱！您看 就在您脚下！
My greatest mistake? I've made a few.
我犯下了大错吗？其实有很多
But there is one I do not intend to make again!
但有一种错误 我绝不会再犯！
No, master, nooooo...
不 主人 不！！！
Ratchet, we need a bridge.
救护车 我们需要传送
You are not the only ones.
需要传送的不只是你们
Everything's back to normal.
一切回归正常
Well, normal for Bumblebee.
至少大黄蜂复原了
It's OK.
没关系
Of course I was.
我当然很勇敢
I know.
我理解
What did he say?
他说什么？
He said thanks.
他说谢谢